Franz Boas Professional Papers ca.1860-1942 Mss.B.B61p
American Philosophical Society
Franz Boas Professional Papers
Circa 1860-1942
Mss.B.B61p
American Philosophical Society
12.5 Linear feet
During the half century leading up to the Second World War, Franz Boas helped to define academic anthropology in the United States. Trained as a geographer at the University of Heidelberg, Boas worked initially on the Inuit of Baffin Island and subsequently on the cultures of the Indians of the Northwest Pacific Coast, becoming a leading figure in American anthropology by the first decade of the twentieth century. As Professor of Anthropology at Columbia University, Boas made significant theoretical contributions to ethnology, linguistics, and physical anthropology, helping to ingrain the four fields approach in his discipline and introducing the concept of cultural relativism into wide currency. He was, as well, a committed Socialist and an ardent opponent of both racism and fascism. The Boas Professional Papers contain a diverse assemblage of professional correspondence, family letters, and diaries, with a valuable series of essays and lectures by Boas on both professional and political topics (democracy, race, etc.).
12.5 lin. feet
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Biographical/Historical note
Born in Minden, Germany, on July 8, 1858, the anthropologist Franz Boas was the son of the merchant Meier Boas and his wife, Sophie Meyer. Raised in the radical and tradition of German Judaism, Franz's youth was steeped in politically liberal beliefs and a largely secular outlook that he carried with him from university through his emigration to the United States.
At the universities of Heidelberg and Bonn, Boas studied physics and geography before completing a doctorate in physical geography at Kiel in 1881. Intending on testing then-current theories of environmental determinism, he signed on to an anthropological expedition to Baffin Island in 1883-1884, expecting that he would document the close adaptative fit of Central Eskimo cultures to their extreme climate. His experiences in the arctic, however, led him to the contrary conclusion: that social traditions, not environmental, exerted a dominant influence over human societies, and from this point onward, he was led to pursue the cultural over than physical dimensions of humanity.
Although he returned to Berlin after the expedition, Boas emigrated to the United States in 1885 to assume an editorial position with the journal Science, hoping to use it as a stepping-stone to an academic appointment. In 1886, he embarked upon a second major field excursion into what would become his most famous ethnographic project, working among the Kwakiutl (Kwakwaka'wakw) Indians of the Northwest Coast, after which he secured his first academic position in 1889, at Clark University in Worcester, Mass. After three years at Clark and a failed appointment at the Field Museum in Chicago in 1892 (during which he played a part in organizing the anthropological exhibits for the Columbian World's Fair), Boas moved to New York City.
The restless activity of Boas's early years slowed in New York. Hired by the American Museum of Natural History (1895-1905), which became the recipient of the amazingly rich anthropological collections he accumulated on the Northwest Coast, Boas began to teach classes at Columbia University in 1896, where three years later he was appointed Professor of Anthropology. For the next 37 years, Boas ruled the anthropological roost at Columbia, accruing unprecedented power in his discipline, wielding grants, recommendations, and appointments with remarkable dexterity, and collecting about him a remarkable group of younger scholars as students and colleagues.
Distancing himself from some of the main currents of contemporary anthropological thought in the United States, and particularly from the evolutionist assumptions that riddled the discipline, Boas championed an anthropology that viewed human cultures as shaped more by historical "tradition" than biological propensity. Claiming to resist any overarching, synthetic theories of human relations, and particularly evolutionary theories of sociocultural development, Boas laid the theoretical groundwork for what became modern cultural relativism. In the process, he helped to clarify the demarcation between the concepts of culture and race and its expression in the divergence of the four fields in anthropology -- linguistics, ethnography, physical anthropology, and archaeology.
Boas's relatively few forays into physical anthropology included a pioneering anthropometric study in 1910-1911, demonstrating that the alleged mental and physical inferiority of immigrants disappeared statistically by the second generation. Opposed to immigration quotas and disdainful of the claims to science used to justify them, Boas was a consistent, strident opponent of racial determinism in intellect or behavior. A committed, politically active Socialist, he was frequently an outspoken critic of American policy. During the First World War, he spoke out against the treatment of German Americans and "enemy aliens" -- to the point of putting himself at risk -- and the rise of the Nazi party in Germany proved an even greater crusade. Despite his age, Boas took an active role in the anti-fascist struggle in the United States and was involved with numerous committees to assist refugee scholars. He was equally ardent in his efforts to criticize racial and ethnic bigotry in the United States.
As a mentor, Boas had a reputation of being directive, at times overbearing, and at the same time of doing too little to prepare his students for the rigors of fieldwork. The extraordinary number of students coming out of Columbia under his care, however, has arguably done as much to extend the Boasian approach than Boas's own writing. Margaret Mead, Ruth Benedict, Elsie Clews Parsons, Alfred Kroeber, Frank Speck, Edward Sapir, Zora Neale Hurston, Ella Deloria, Melville Herskovits, Leslie Spier, Paul Radin, and Ashley Montagu are all students of Boas. Many continued in the same intellectual stream, some diverged, yet all bore traces of Boas's influence. He left a mark as well on the institutions of the discipline, as one of the founders of the American Anthropological Association and of the International Journal of American Linguistics.
Scope and Contents note
The Boas Professional Papers contain a diverse assemblage of professional correspondence, family letters, and diaries, with a valuable series of essays and lectures by Boas on both professional and political topics (democracy, race, etc.). Of particular note are his Clark University lectures of 1898 and extensive data from his 1883-1884 expedition to Baffin Island to study cultural adaptation among the Inuit. The collection includes a diary, maps, photographs (a few here, supplemented by others in the main Boas Photograph collection), a sketchbook and sketches. It also includes valuable material on Boas's research on the Kwakiutl, including ethnographic texts, linguistic data, and extensive correspondence with George Hunt. Boas's work with the American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom (1940-1942) is well documented in the collection, as are his interests in the American Council of Learned Societies and its Committee on Native American Languages, Columbia University, and U.S. v. Tatos Cartozian, an interesting Armenian naturalization case of 1924-1925.
The 4.5 linear feet of correspondence from Boas in the collection is comprised primarily of letters to his family from the 1860s until his death in 1942, along with diaries for 1886, 1888, 1889. There are, as well, related Boas family letters and documents, extensive correspondence with Ernst Boas, 1898-1937 (including reminiscences of his father), and an 1880 diary kept by Boas' wife, Marie.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Helene Boas Yampolsky, 1961-1962; and Cecil Yampolsky, 1964.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Some diaries and notebooks have been microfilmed (film 1445).
Related Archival Materials note
Other Franz Boas Collections
Franz Boas Papers, 1862-1942 (Mss B B61)
View Collection
Boas Family Papers, 1862-1942 (Mss B B61f)
View Collection
Boas-Rukeyser Collection, 1869-1940 (Mss B B61ru)
View Collection
Franz Boas field notebooks and anthropometric data, ca. 1883-1912 (Mss B B61.5)
View Collection
The American Council of Learned Societies Committee on Native American Languages, Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics ( Mss 497.3.B63c) is a large collection of primary materials on Native American languages assembled, in part, under Boas's supervision, and including a large quantity of material written by Boas himself.
Boas appears as a correspondent in numerous APS collections, and in addition to its rich collections for the history of anthropology, the library houses the papers of several of Boas's former students and proteges, including Frank Speck ( Mss. Ms. Coll. 126), Elsie Clews Parsons ( Mss. Ms. Coll. 29), John Alden Mason ( Mss. B M384), Paul Radin ( Mss. 497.3 R114), and Ashley Montagu ( Mss. Ms. Coll. 109).
The APS also houses a microfilm (372.3, reel 1) of original materials in the Office of Anthropology Archives, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., relating to Boas's trips to Baffin Island (N.W.T.) and British Columbia, during which he studied and collected cultural materials, 1885-1909.
The papers of Boas's son Ernst Boas ( Mss. Ms. Coll. 10) are housed at the APS. A physician, Ernst Boas shared his father's liberal political outlook and activist social views.
Bibliography
Rohner, Ronald P., ed., The Ethnography of Franz Boas: Letters and Diaries of Franz Boas, Written on the Northwest Coast from 1886 to 1931 (Chicago: Univ. of Chicago, 1969). Call no.: B B61e.r
Stocking, George, ed., The Shaping of American Anthropology, 1883-1911: A Franz Boas Reader (N.Y.: Basic Books, 1974). Call no.: 572.081 B63s
Cole, Douglas, Franz Boas: The Early Years, 1859-1906 (Seattle: Univ. of Washington, 1999).
Boas, Franz, The Mind of Primitive Man (N.Y.: MacMillan, 1911). Call no.: 572 B63m
Boas, Franz, Ethnology of the Kwakiutl (Washington, D.C.:Government Printing Office, 1921). Call no.: 572.97 B63e
Boas, Franz, Primitive Art (Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard Univ. Press, 1927). Call no.: 571.7 B63p
Boas, Franz, ed., General Anthropology (Boston: D.C. Heath, 1938). Call no.: 572 B63g.r
Boas, Franz, Race, Language and Culture (N.Y.: MacMillan, 1940). Call no.: 572.081 B63r
American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom.; American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Native American; Boas, Ernst P., (Ernst Philip), 1891-1955; Boas, Marie Anna Ernestina Krackowizer, 1861-1929; Cartozian, Tatos; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944; Deloria, Ella Cara; Efron, David; Fortune, Reo, 1903-1979; Hunt, George; Lowie, Robert Harry, 1883-1957; Reichard, Gladys Amanda, 1893-1955; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939; Weike, Wilhelm, 1859-1917; Anthropologists -- United States.; Anthropology--Research--United States; Anthropology--United States.; Arctic regions--Discovery and exploration; Baffin Island (N.W.T.); Diaries.; Eskimos--Baffin Island (N.W.T.); Ethnology--North America; Indians of North America--Ethnology; Indians of North America--Languages; Indians of North America--Northwest Coast; Inuit; Jewish scientists; Kwakiutl Indians; Kwakiutl language; Languages; Lectures; Photographs; Refugees, Political; Scientific expeditions -- Arctic regions.; Scientists, Refugee; Sketches.; Socialists--United States; Tlingit Indians
- Franz Boas Professional Papers, ca.1860-1942; Collection II; 12.5 linear feet
  - Aall, A. (Box 1)
  - Adamson, Thelma (Box 1)
  - Adler, Herman M. (Box 1)
  - Adler, Mortimer J. -- The Social Scientist's Misconception of Science (Box 1)
  - American Anthropologic Association (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science. - Committee on Introduction of Anthropologic Teaching (Box 1)
  - American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom, 18 folders (Box 1)
  - American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom - Minutes, 1941 (Box 1)
  - American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom - Minutes, 1942 (Box 1)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), 4 folders (Box 1)
  - American League of the Brotherhood of Man (Box 1)
  - American Scientific Societies - Publications, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Americanists' Congress, Hague & Goteburg, Resolution concerning transcribing American Indian languages, 1924 - (Box 1)
  - Anglo-American University Library for Central Europe, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Angulo, Jaime de (Box 1)
  - Anthropological Field Work, Reports, 1933-34. (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    [Armenians and their race]
  - Atlantic Monthly, [1917-18].; 1 p. (inc.) (Box 1)
    [German-American press]
  - Austin, Mary (Box 1)
  - Bache Research Fund (Box 1)
  - Bailey, L. H. (Box 1)
  - Barbeau, Charles M. - Tsimshian texts (Box 1)
  - Barnard College (Box 1)
  - Barnes, Earl (Box 1)
  - Bastian, Adolph (Box 1)
  - Bendam, Effie (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Ruth - "Franz Boas", 1943 (Box 2)
  - Birket-Smith, Kaj (Box 2)
  - Bloomfield, Leonard (Box 2)
  - [Blum --]. Concerning Kinship system (Box 2)
  - [Blumensohn, Jules Henry] - "Consonantic Scheme", 1933 (Box 2)
  - Boas, Franz (Box 2-17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Academic courses (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Account of expenditures (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Accounts and budgets for research (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Address book, 1929 (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Addresses, Residential, (1889-1942) (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Affidavit concerning race, 1937 (Box 2)
      General note
      - Arctic Exped - [UNK] [UNK] Articles
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Diary, 1883-1884; 21 folders (Box 2)
      Native American Images note
      Folder #21: Sketches
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Diary (Translation), 1883-1884; 7 folders (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Diary Synopsis, 1883 (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Diary, 1883 June-1883 October (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Diary, 1883 September 5 - 10 (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Maps, ca.1883 (Box 2)
      - Chart of Niantilic harbour by William A. Mintzer, U.S. Navy, from observations by Lieutenant Wilkins, U.S. Navy, navigating officer of the U.S. St. Tigress on Polaris search, 1874; 178: 1874: M667nia: Small; 1 map, 25.9 x 20.6 cm; Mintzer, William A.; Wilkins, Lieutenant (Map-case Small)
        Scale: 1/2 inch = 1 mile
        Other Finding Aids note
        Realms of Gold, 6 (1).
      - Baffinland--Arctic Expedition, ca. 1883; 2 maps, 31.8 x 28.6 cm; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942 (Box 2)
        Route from American Harbor to Kingawa and return. Colored.
        Realms of Gold, 6 (4).
      - Hudson Bay, Baffin Bay and Greenland area, ca. 1883; 2 maps, 35.9 x 35.6 cm; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942 (Box 2)
        Printed map with travel routes marked in red and blue pencil.
        Realms of Gold, 6 (2).
      - Sketch of area from Arsebemiling to Ipiakdiuak, ca. 1883; 1 map, 30.8 x 30.5 cm; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942 (Box 2)
        Rough pencil sketch. On the verso is a map of Niantilik harbor.
        Realms of Gold, 6 (3).
      - The Eskimo tribes of north-east America, ca. 1888; 610: [ca. 1888]: B638etr: Small; 1 map, 19 3/8 in. x 17 3/16 in.; Bien, Julius, 1826-1909; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942 (Map-case Small)
        Colored.
        See: U.S. Bureau of American Ethnology. Franz Boas, "The Central Eskimo." Sixth Annual Report.
        Immediate Source of Acquisition note
        Presented by Mrs. Helene Boas Yampolsky, 1961-1962.
        Realms of Gold, 486.
      - Map showing in detail the geographical divisions of territory occupied by the Eskimo tribes of northeastern America, ca. 1888; 610: [ca. 1888]: B638est: Small; 1 map, 20 7/8 in. x 18 3/4 in.; Bien, Julius, 1826-1909; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942 (Map-case Small)
        Colored. Includes 1. Oqo and Akudnirn; 2. Frobisher Bay; 3. Eclipse Sound and Lyon inlet; 4. Repulse Bay and Lyon inlet; 5. Boothia Isthmus and King William Land.
        Realms of Gold, 487.
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Notebook [Typed translation], 1884 January 1 (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Outline of proposed trip, 1883 (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Plants, ca.1883 (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Photographs, ca.1883 (Box 2)
      Inuit
      - Kwakiutl woman and child, ca. 1883 (Box 2)
      - Kwakiutl girl, 1883-1886; U4.1.37
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Sketchbook, 1883 (Box 2)
    - Boas, Franz -- Arctic Expedition - Sketches, ca.1883 (Box 2)
      - Arctic Expedition, ca. 1883 (Box 2)
    - [Boas, Franz] -- Baffinland and the Eskimos (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Baffinland Diary, 1883 (Box 22)
    - Boas, Franz -- Baffinland Diary and Notebook, 1883 June (Box 22)
    - Boas, Franz -- Baffinland Notebook, 1883 (Box 22)
    - Boas, Franz -- Baffinland Notebook, 1883-1884 (Box 22)
      Sketches, letters, maps.
    - Boas, Franz -- Bibliography (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Biographical information (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Biographical sketch of William J. McGee, n. d. (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Boas family life (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Book contracts (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Broadside. "Preserving our Ideals" (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Certificates and diplomas (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Condolences on the death of Boas (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Cooperation between the Department of Anthropology, Columbia University, and the American Museum of Natural History (Box 3)
    - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1850s-1942, n.d. (Box 3-12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, Early - 1869 (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1870 (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1871 (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1872 (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1873 (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1874 (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1875 (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1876 July - Sept. (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1876 October (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1877 Feb. - March (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1877 April (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1877 May (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1877 June (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1877 July - Aug. (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1877 Sept. - Oct. (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1877 Nov. - Dec. (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1878 Jan. (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1878 Feb. (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1878 March (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1878 May - June (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1878 July - Aug. (Box 3)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1878 Sept. - Dec. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1879 Jan. - Feb. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1879 March - April (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1879 May (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1879 June - July (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1879 Aug. - Dec. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1880 Jan. - April (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1880 May - July (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1880 Aug. - Sept. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1880 Oct. - Dec. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence. Transcriptions, 1880 (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1881 Jan. - March (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1881 April - July (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1881 Aug. - Jan. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence. Transcriptions, 1881 (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1882 (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence. Transcriptions, 1882 (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1883 Jan. - Feb. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1883 April - May (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1883 June 1 - 14 (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1883 June 16 - 30 (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1883 Aug. - Sept. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1883 Oct. - Dec. (Box 4)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1884 April - July (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1884 Sept. (Box 5)
        Sketches
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1884 Oct. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1884 Nov. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1884 Dec. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 Jan. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 Feb. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 March (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 April (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 May (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 June (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 July (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 Aug. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 Sept. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 Oct. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 Nov. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1885 Dec. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 Jan. - Feb. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 March - April (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 May (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 June (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 July - Aug. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 Sept. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 Oct. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 Nov. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1886 Dec. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1887 Jan. - Feb. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1887 March - April (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1887 May - June (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1887 July - Aug. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1887 Sept. - Oct. (Box 5)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1887 Nov. - Dec. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1888 Jan. - March (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1888 April - May (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1888 July - Aug. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1888 Sept. - Oct. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1888 Nov. - Dec. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1889 Jan. - Mar. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1889 April - July (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1889 Aug. - Sept. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1889 Oct. - Dec. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1890 Jan. - Feb. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1890 March - April (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1890 May - June (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1890 July (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1890 Aug. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1890 Sept. - Oct. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1890 Nov. - Dec. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1891 Jan. - March (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1891 Apr. - June (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1891 June (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1891 July; 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1891 Aug. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1891 Sept. - Oct. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1891 Nov. - Dec. (Box 6)